<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Desmond Rivet - All Posts</title>
  
  <subtitle>The firehose of all my posts</subtitle>
  
  <icon>https://desmondrivet.com/static/img/me03.jpg</icon>
  <link href="https://desmondrivet.com/posts/feed_all.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="https://desmondrivet.com/posts/"/>
  <updated>2024-11-26T00:58:42Z</updated>
  <id>https://desmondrivet.com/posts/</id>
  <author>
    <name>Desmond Rivet</name>
    <email>desmond.rivet@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Madrid Is the Toronto of Spain, and That's Okay</title>
    <link href="https://desmondrivet.com/2024/11/25/madrid-exit"/>
    <updated>2024-11-26T00:58:42Z</updated>
    <id>https://desmondrivet.com/2024/11/25/madrid-exit</id>
    <content type="html">
        


        &lt;p&gt;Madrid marked the end of our trip to Spain.  Our plane home flew out of
there and so we decided to spend the evening before exploring what we could
of the city.  We boarded a train from Seville and arrived at our hotel
around 4pm that day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would argue Madrid is the Toronto of Spain from the point of view of
visiting Canadians because, like Toronto, it's the largest city in the
country as well as its economic hub and &lt;em&gt;also&lt;/em&gt; the city that everyone loves
to hate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've said this before but I'll say it again - everyone loves Barcelona.  No
one loves Madrid.  Madrid, by all popular accounts, is mediocre at best.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Side note: if Madrid is the Toronto of Spain, does this mean that Barcelona
is the Montreal of Spain?  I don't think the comparison is crazy - everyone
&lt;em&gt;loves&lt;/em&gt; Montreal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having visited Madrid, I can now say that, like Toronto, I feel its
reputation is somewhat undeserved - at least from the little I saw of it.
It appears to be a clean, attractive, organized city, marred only by the
confusing public transit system.  The buildings seem newer and less
distinctive, which I imagine puts some people off, but I thought they looked
pretty decent.  It's definitely not as dynamic as Barcelona or as colourful
as Seville but I honestly found the calm, almost placid vibe rather
refreshing after 10 days of hustle and bustle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like Barcelona, it feels like there's a real city here, with a life of its
own beyond the tourists.  I could certainly see myself visiting again.&lt;/p&gt;

    </content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>A Distinct Lack of Barbers</title>
    <link href="https://desmondrivet.com/2024/11/25/seville"/>
    <updated>2024-11-26T00:10:38Z</updated>
    <id>https://desmondrivet.com/2024/11/25/seville</id>
    <content type="html">
        


        &lt;p&gt;I'm 47 years old, and most of the people I work with are much younger than I
am - often in their 20's and 30's.  Cultural references that I think are
universal sometimes turn out to be pretty specific to my age group in ways
that surprise me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take something like Bugs Bunny.  Most people, young and old, have of course
&lt;em&gt;heard&lt;/em&gt; of Bugs Bunny but it turns out that not a lot of young people grew
up watching it.  I have, and it is &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=iiYW2d7RWw4"&gt;because of this cartoon&lt;/a&gt; that I
happen to vaguely know some of the music to &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Barber_of_Seville"&gt;The Barber of Seville&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So when I told some of my workmates that I was visiting Seville, and that I
would be visiting all the famous sites &lt;em&gt;as well as a barber&lt;/em&gt;, no one got the
joke.  They took one look at my shaved head and with genuine confusion would
proceed to inform me that I have no hair and hence would not need the
services of a barber.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Growing old is &lt;em&gt;awful&lt;/em&gt;, y'all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway! After &lt;a href="https://desmondrivet.com/2024/10/25/barcelona"&gt;Barcelona&lt;/a&gt;, Evelyn and I hopped on a high-speed train and
headed to Seville.  We had booked 3 nights.  It's not a destination you
often hear about in connection with a trip to Spain, but I had heard that it
was beautiful, and well worth the visit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had &lt;em&gt;also&lt;/em&gt; heard that it was &amp;quot;underrated&amp;quot; and so I had assumed that it
would be less crowded than Barcelona.  Was I right?  Let's find out!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Arrival&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our apartment was located across from &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Metropol_Parasol"&gt;Las Setas&lt;/a&gt;, an odd, mushroom
shaped structure a short walk from the Old Town.  The accommodations were a
cross between an Airbnb and a hotel - it was a full apartment with fridge
and stove, but we didn't have to share the place with anyone.  Nice enough
digs, and a damn sight quieter than Barcelona.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In terms of location, we were about a half hour walk from the Plaza de
Espana, which I was desperate to see right away.  &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Plaza_de_Espa%C3%B1a,_Seville"&gt;Plaza de Espana&lt;/a&gt; is
the &amp;quot;postcard&amp;quot; attraction of Seville - it's what shows up when you search
for &amp;quot;Seville&amp;quot; in a search engine and choose &amp;quot;images&amp;quot;.  Try it and you'll see
what I mean, and you'll also understand why I wanted to see this thing so
bad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best way to get to the Plaza de Espana is to go through the &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Santa_Cruz,_Seville"&gt;Barrio de
Santa Cruz&lt;/a&gt;, otherwise known as the Old Town, or Jewish Quarter, a
gorgeously colourful collection of narrow streets, alleyways and squares.
It reminded me a bit of El Born in Barcelona but way less gritty and better
maintained - so well maintained, in fact, that Evelyn thought the whole
thing looked a bit unreal, like a theme park.  I could see where she was
coming from and I didn't entirely disagree, but I still found myself
enjoying the neighbourhood's twists and turns, even if I was sharing the
experience with thousands of other tourists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So...Seville is definitely &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; some kinda of underrated &amp;quot;secret&amp;quot;.  It was
definitely crowded, though the tourist demographic may have skewed a little
bit older than Barcelona.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Santa Cruz is home to some of the most popular tourist attractions in the
city, like the Cathedral and the Royal Alcazar and though these were
definitely on my list of things to see - I had already bought tickets for
both of them for the following day - at the moment I had my sights set on
the Plaza.  From the direction we were going, we approached it from behind,
turned a corner and...voila.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's hard to describe what hits your eyes when you turn the corner.
It's...immense, certainly, and your breath catches, but that's not quite the
whole story.  The entire package just sort of catches your eye, from the
square in front of the building, to the colourful, tiled mosaics, to the
symmetrical twin towers on either end, to the little stream running through
it all.  It's just...stunning, in a quite literal way - I was speechless for
a few seconds when I saw it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was surprised to learn that the Plaza de Espana isn't actually very old;
it was built in 1929 for the Seville World Fair.  It was designed to
impress, and accomplishes the goal effortlessly.  I was more disappointed to
learn that the building now houses mostly government offices but I guess you
got to do &lt;em&gt;something&lt;/em&gt; with all that space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also: not that I was looking very hard, but I did not find a barber this
day.  I &lt;em&gt;did&lt;/em&gt; however, find &lt;a href="https://desmondrivet.com/2024/10/05/sevile-misc/9957c8b1e5ed91"&gt;Rosina's Balcony&lt;/a&gt;, by all accounts the
inspiration for the opera.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Second Day&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next day was reserved for our two main paid attractions in Seville: the
&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alc%C3%A1zar_of_Seville"&gt;Royal Alcazar&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Seville_Cathedral"&gt;Seville Cathedral&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First up was the Royal Alcazar, the Spanish royal family's official
residence when they stay in Seville.  It looks like something out of
Morocco.  At first I thought it was actually built by Moorish invaders but,
alas, the truth is a bit more mundane.  Though originally the site of a 10th
century Islamic citadel, progressive conquests and reconstructions have led
to current palace, a Mudéjar-style estate dating back to the 14th century,
near the end of Islamic rule in Spain.  It &lt;em&gt;looks&lt;/em&gt; like something
&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Scheherazade"&gt;Scheherazade&lt;/a&gt; may have cooked up but it was actually built by European
Christians as a Christian residence, though very much in the style of the
conquering Moors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The place is mind-blowing.  To some extent, I suppose, it must have been the
novelty of the whole thing - I'd never seen anything quite it.  When you
visit Europe, you're used to seeing a lot of churches and castles and
palaces of a certain look and feel, and the Alcazar just doesn't fit that
mould.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the tour was over, we had lunch, walked a bit and then stood in line
for the Seville Cathedral.  Like the Alcazar, the church has Islamic origins
and was originally the site of a large mosque.  Nothing remains of the
original structure except, notably, the &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Giralda"&gt;Giralda tower&lt;/a&gt;, which totally
looks the part.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I usually don't bother with church tours when I visit Europe, but this one
came highly recommended, for reasons I didn't fully grasp until I saw it.
The Seville Cathedral is the largest Gothic cathedral in the world and
although I understand what that means &lt;em&gt;abstractly&lt;/em&gt; it's still a big hit to
the brain when you go inside and see just what that means in practice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I could say that it's huge, but what does that even mean?  Legend has it
that the architects wanted to build a church so big the world thought they
were crazy.  Mission accomplished - the size is impossible to convey in
words, and difficult in photos (I &lt;a href="https://desmondrivet.com/2024/10/05/seville-cathedral.html"&gt;tried&lt;/a&gt;, and mostly failed, I think).
Let's just say that when you go inside you feel very, very, very small.  My
first reaction was to wonder how on earth they keep the ceilings clean.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are, reportedly, over 80 chapels (distinct altars or areas where
people can kneel and pray) inside but, again, I'm not exactly sure what I'm
supposed to do with that information.  How many chapels does a church
usually have?  I have no idea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; know is that the main chapel is called, unsurprisingly, the Main
Chapel, and that it houses one of the most breathtaking works of art I've
ever seen in my life: the &lt;a href="https://yatrikaone.com/spain-seville-cathedral-altarpiece-at-the-main-chapel/"&gt;Ritablo Mayor&lt;/a&gt;, or Main Altarpiece, an
unassuming name for something so incredibly &lt;em&gt;extra&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Ritablo Mayor stands roughly 60 feet tall and consists of matrix or grid
of Bible scenes, all carved out of wood and gilded to the hilt.  In a time
when most people couldn't read, this was meant to familiarize them with
selected Bible stories, the way a comic book might today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh! And the Cathedral is also the final resting place of one Christopher
Columbus.  An asshole, to be sure, but the history is deep here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Side note: on this second day, I still did not find a barber.  Is there just
one barber in Seville, the one the opera's about?  It feels like it.  Anyway
I didn't find him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Third Day&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The third day in Seville was mostly just exploration and if you're going to
do that, one neighbourhood stands out: &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Triana,_Seville"&gt;Triana&lt;/a&gt;.  At least, that's what
the Internet and guidebooks say, which means that it's still just as
touristy as the rest of town.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm being a bit unfair.  Triana definitely had a lot of tourists but it also
had a lot of stretches that just seemed...uninteresting.  Therein lies rub
when it comes to the dichotomy between &amp;quot;authentic&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;touristy&amp;quot;.
Generally speaking, touristy places are like that for a reason - and, by
contrast, the non-touristy, authentic spots are &lt;em&gt;also&lt;/em&gt; like that for a
reason.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we first crossed the bridge to Trina, for example, after a bit of
wandering, we settled on a bar that felt pretty local.  It wasn't a bad
spot, and the food was okay, but...it was definitely not catering to us.  I
think people sometimes don't realize that &amp;quot;real&amp;quot; Spaniards drink local beer
and eat fries and pizza like the rest of us.  I honestly think the place
could have become better over upon multiple visits but we never got the
chance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It turns out that we actually crossed the wrong bridge.  We meant to cross
the Puente de Isabel II, which was supposed to take us directly into the
main part of the neighbourhood, with all the popular restaurants and bars,
but instead we crossed a bridge or two earlier and ended up in a part of
town that was much more residential and local - as represented by the bar we
settled on.  We didn't quite know where we were, and we couldn't quite
figure out why there wasn't anything interesting around us.  Again, it all
comes back to be authentic versus touristy, and being careful what you wish
for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, Trina as a whole definitely had a totally different vibe from the
Old Town.  While the Old Town felt a bit like a theme park, Trina felt like
a real neighbourhood, like people actually lived there.  It probably
deserves more exploration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Seriously, where are all the barbers?  I couldn't even find one in Triana,
and &lt;em&gt;this&lt;/em&gt; time I was actually looking.  I guess tourists don't really need
their hair cut)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Comparison with Barcelona&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inevitably, when I tell people that I went to both Seville and Barcelona,
people will ask me which I prefer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's a tough question to answer, because I genuinely liked both cities.  I
&lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; say, however, that while I think Seville is a prettier town than
Barcelona, I felt that there was more going on in the latter.  Seville felt
like a town of tourist attractions, and you begin to think that there's
maybe not much going on beyond that.  Barcelona &lt;em&gt;also&lt;/em&gt; has a ton of tourist
attractions, but one gets the impression that there's an honest-to-goodness
city to be explored once you move past them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So on the whole I guess Barcelona has a slight edge here, though I would
gladly revisit both.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Ironically, on the train &lt;em&gt;out&lt;/em&gt; of Seville to Madrid...we finally caught
sight of a barber shop.  I think Seville is missing out on a lucrative
opportunity here)&lt;/p&gt;

    </content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title/>
    <link href="https://desmondrivet.com/2024/11/09/125358"/>
    <updated>2024-11-09T17:53:58Z</updated>
    <id>https://desmondrivet.com/2024/11/09/125358</id>
    <content type="html">
        

<p>Like of <a class="u-like-of dont-break-out" href="https://adactio.com/journal/21548">https://adactio.com/journal/21548</a></p>


        
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Looking for Paella in All the Wrong Places</title>
    <link href="https://desmondrivet.com/2024/10/25/barcelona"/>
    <updated>2024-10-26T00:38:02Z</updated>
    <id>https://desmondrivet.com/2024/10/25/barcelona</id>
    <content type="html">
        


        &lt;p&gt;The COVID-19 pandemic put a cramp in my travel habits, as it did with
everyone.  The last overseas trip that Evelyn and I went on was &lt;a href="https://desmondrivet.com/2016/06/29/poland"&gt;to
Poland&lt;/a&gt; in 2016 for a wedding and the last one that we actually &lt;em&gt;planned&lt;/em&gt;
was &lt;a href="https://desmondrivet.com/2015/07/11/trip-greece"&gt;to Greece&lt;/a&gt; in 2015 (and, my God, it's hard for me to accept that
Greece &lt;em&gt;9 years ago&lt;/em&gt;).  We've been to a handful of relatively local
destinations in the interim (Vancouver, New York, PEI) but nothing
particularly foreign.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And while I do remain part of an increasingly small minority of people who
still thinks about the pandemic in the present tense, I &lt;em&gt;also&lt;/em&gt; wanted to
finally visit someplace a bit more exotic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So...with our vaccines topped up, we choose Spain. Or rather I choose it,
and I dragged Evelyn along.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wanted to avoid a repeat of the madness of Greece.  We managed to pack a
lot into 10 days for that trip, and it was all great, but the trade off was
that we were constantly on the move, never staying more than a couple of
days in one spot.  I wanted something a bit more stable this time so we
settled on 6 nights in Barcelona, 3 nights in Seville and 1 night in Madrid
since we were flying out of there the next day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The trip was planned just as locals started protesting mass tourism in Spain
and other parts of Europe, and while I'd hoped that travelling in September
would spare us the worst of it, I also got some advice on how to blend
in...or at least on how to avoid walking around with a giant neon arrow
pointed at my head flashing &amp;quot;tourist&amp;quot;.  Mostly this involved dressing
plainly and not being obnoxious.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started making inquiries.  What was Spain like?  What was worth seeing?
What wasn't?  From the very few people I talked to, the consensus seemed to
be that:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Barcelona was amazing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Seville was amazing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The food was amazing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Madrid was...not amazing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Were we attacked with water guns?  Was the food indeed amazing?  Exactly how
disappointing was Madrid?  Read on to find out!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Or rather, read on to find out more about Barcelona!  Seville and Madrid
will be dealt with in a future blog entry since this one is getting quite
long).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;There is No Barcelona Syndrome&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our first stop was Barcelona, our home for the next few days.  Before we get
into it though, I want to take a small detour and talk about another famous
and tourist-laden European city: Paris.  In particular, I want to talk about
something called &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Paris_syndrome"&gt;Paris Syndrome&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paris Syndrome is the cognitive dissonance felt by many tourists when they
visit a legendary city like Paris.  It's the contrast between knowing in
your heart of hearts that Paris is the very epitome of European high-culture
and the fact that, when you visit, there are rude people and &lt;a href="https://www.npr.org/2013/01/26/170321680/not-just-a-fashion-hot-spot-paris-is-also-the-capital-of-dog-mess"&gt;dog shit&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;em&gt;everywhere&lt;/em&gt;.  It's particularly common among Japanese tourists, who tend to
put the city on a pedestal and who tend to come from places where, I can
only assume, people are more polite and tend to pick up after their pets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One interesting twist to all of this is that I didn't actually experience
Paris Syndrome when I first visited the city 20 odd years ago.  I wasn't
very well-travelled, and Europe was still so new to me back then, that every
street, every back alley, no matter how mundane, took on an air of the
exotic for the simple reason that it &lt;em&gt;wasn't home&lt;/em&gt;.  It's not that I didn't
notice the dog shit - I most definitely noticed it - but rather that it lent
an &amp;quot;interesting&amp;quot; texture to a place that was already bearing down on me with
the weight of its history.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or maybe part of it is that I come from Montreal, a city with its share of
grime.  The dog shit didn't faze me as much as some people.  Who knows?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, with that in mind, I would like to point out that there doesn't appear
to be such a thing as Barcelona Syndrome - at least, not according to
Wikipedia.  Everyone I've talked to raves about the place.  Madrid?  You can
skip it.  Barcelona?  Don't you fucking &lt;em&gt;dare&lt;/em&gt;.  The food, the architecture,
the beaches - by all accounts Barcelona walks on water in a way that Paris
does not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why is this?  Is Barcelona that amazing?  Or is it that it doesn't have
quite the same lofty reputation as Paris, and so people's expectations are
lower?  I don't know, but I'll say this.  When I was discussing with Evelyn
how long we would stay, she expressed concern that 5 days would too much.
She was genuinely concerned that we would be bored after day 3.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since Paris, of course, I've been back to Europe several times and while
many parts of it are indeed achingly beautiful, I've now &amp;quot;been there&amp;quot; and
&amp;quot;done that&amp;quot;, so to speak.  I'm no longer impressed by something just because
it's different or &amp;quot;exotic&amp;quot; and I can safely say that it takes more than just
a slightly foreign looking alleyway to engage my sense of wonder.  And dog
shit, no two ways about it, is a blight on society.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, given that this isn't my first rodeo, but &lt;em&gt;also&lt;/em&gt; that everyone really,
&lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; seems to love Barcelona...how was it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Less Vibes, More Sights, and Gaudi All Around&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let's start with the Airbnb.  It was located in the Barcelona Sans district,
right near the train station, and only a 5 minute walk from the metro.
While our accommodations were modest, our hostess was legitimately one of
the friendliest people I've ever met in my life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's where I learned that Duo Lingo is a lie.  Our hostess spoke Ukrainian
and Spanish - but not much English.  No problem, I think to myself - I've
been Duo Lingo-ing Spanish for a over a year and we should be fine, right?
Right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hahahahaha!  I don't know if I'm just bad at this but my Spanish was
&lt;em&gt;rough&lt;/em&gt;, y'all.  As in, non-existent.  We desperately ended up relying on
Google Translate here.  This linguistic problem actually cropped up more
than you might imagine given that we were tourists in one of the most
heavily visited cities in the world.  You see, our attempts to blend in
&lt;em&gt;actually worked&lt;/em&gt; - kind of.  Random people would stop us to ask for
directions, in Spanish, only to be met with a laughably broken &amp;quot;No hablo
espanol&amp;quot;.  Devastating.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still, our room was decent enough and very well situated, so it was hard to
complain.  And while no part of Barcelona is completely tourist-free, this
area wasn't completely overrun with them, so that was a win.  The
neighbourhood felt...lived in.  Pleasant enough, but I didn't get the
impression that everything was there &lt;em&gt;for us&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our first touristy thing to do was booked for the night we flew in - a tour
of &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Casa_Batll%C3%B3"&gt;Casa Batllo&lt;/a&gt;, by all accounts a &amp;quot;must see&amp;quot;, and so we decided we &amp;quot;had
to&amp;quot; see it.  It's a building designed by &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Antoni_Gaud%C3%AD"&gt;Antoni Gaudi&lt;/a&gt;, a name that
comes up again and again in connection to Barcelona - it sometimes feels
like he designed half the city.  For what it's worth, it's an impressive
structure - the thing looked like it was made from bones; indeed, I later
discovered that the locals sometimes call it the House of Bones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This feels like a good spot to point out something that immediately sets
Barcelona apart from Paris in my mind, either because I'm less of a
wide-eyed traveller nowadays or because of something intrinsically different
between the two cities.  Paris, to me at least, is the type of city where
you can just kind of...soak up the vibe.  Obviously, there are a ton of
specific things to see and do, but it's &lt;em&gt;also&lt;/em&gt; possible to just amble along
aimlessly and still feel like you're experiencing something special and
unique.  There's less of that in Barcelona.  The city feels grittier, and
lazily strolling around is a less interesting experience.  Don't get me
wrong, there's a ton of cool things to see and do, but it's less vibe and
more sights, if that makes sense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite being so crowded, there isn't much dog shit or trash in Barcelona
and that night, in bed, we discovered why.  It's because the city empties
out the garbage bins &lt;em&gt;every single night&lt;/em&gt;.  We were woken up to the sounds
of glass bottles being crushed in a garbage truck around 2 am.  Good thing
we brought earplugs.  I was prepared the next night.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Interesting philosophical question: if this had happened while I was in
Paris, would I have chalked it up to the &amp;quot;texture&amp;quot; of the city?  I don't
know but I can tell you that I was certainly not impressed this time
around).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next day we toured the &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sagrada_Fam%C3%ADlia"&gt;Sagrada Familia&lt;/a&gt;, another Gaudi special.
Nominally a Catholic Basilica, I can safely say that the Sagrada Familia was
one of the top things I'll forever remember about Barcelona.  As one starts
to experience more of Gaudi's work, you begin to notice similar themes.  The
guy was really into making his creations look organic - &lt;em&gt;grown&lt;/em&gt; rather than
&lt;em&gt;designed&lt;/em&gt;.  Sometimes that meant making them look like they were built from
bones, and sometimes it meant making them look like they were crystals
jutting out of the ground.  In the case of the Sagrada Familia, it looked
like &lt;em&gt;both&lt;/em&gt;.  I was surprised to learn that it's not the official Cathedral
of Barcelona (that title goes to the much more aptly name &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Barcelona_Cathedral"&gt;Barcelona
Cathedral&lt;/a&gt; - by all accounts a much less impressive structure) but given
that, due to Gaudi's untimely death, it's still not finished after 150
years, I suppose it's not surprising.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later that day we visited &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Park_G%C3%BCell"&gt;Park Guell&lt;/a&gt;, yet another Gaudi creation (this
guy is &lt;em&gt;everywhere&lt;/em&gt; in Barcelona).  Not quite the jaw dropping spectacle of
the Sagrada Familia, Park Guell still looks like something out of
Dr. Seuss.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;A Brief Culinary Detour&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We obviously had to eat that night and so now might be good time to talk
about the food.  It's definitely one of things people tend to comment on
when they talk about Spain.  People seem to love it.  When questioned on the
subject, a friend of mine remarked: &amp;quot;Two words: &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jam%C3%B3n_ib%C3%A9rico"&gt;jamón ibérico&lt;/a&gt;&amp;quot;.
Another friend won't stop talking about the &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Paella"&gt;paella&lt;/a&gt; and yet another
friend raves about the tapas, which is weird because tapas aren't really a
&lt;em&gt;recipe&lt;/em&gt;, right?  More of a...portion size?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I'll get this out of the way: the food was...fine.  Tasty, but not mind
blowing.  Just okay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe it's because I've visited France and Italy where the food was, indeed,
mind blowing, but I found the food in Spain a bit lackluster.  I'm honestly
not sure what the big deal is about paella; I tried it three times and it
was certainly &lt;em&gt;good&lt;/em&gt; each time but people treat this dish like it's some
kind of religious experience it just...was not that for me.  To be fair,
it's possible that we simply picked the wrong spots - I'm pretty sure at
least of them was a tourist trap - but it's hard for me to imagine even a
professionally prepared paella changing my life.  I'm willing to be
corrected here!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And the jamón ibérico?  People will yell at you if you call it prosciutto,
so I won't call it prosciutto, but it's definitely prosciutto &lt;em&gt;adjacent&lt;/em&gt;,
you know?  It's delicious, but I've had similar stuff before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One Spanish culinary item that did, in fact, stand out for me might not be
what you expect: it was the vermouth.  Vermerterias, bars that specialize in
vermouth, are &lt;em&gt;everywhere&lt;/em&gt; in Spain, many of them with their own house
blends.  Vermouth gets a bad rap in North America - it's the stuff you
&lt;em&gt;grudgingly&lt;/em&gt; mix into a Martini or a Manhattan - but &lt;em&gt;good&lt;/em&gt; vermouth is
criminally underrated, and Spain is awash in the stuff.  It was great.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh!  And the cheesecake.  I actually really, really liked the cheesecake.
It's definitely not like the firm, dense, almost crumbly cheesecake you get
here, which I also love.  Spanish cheesecake is less cake and more creamy
custard.  You almost eat it like a pudding.  It's amazing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;El Born and the Gothic Quarter&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the advice of a friend, we booked a free (sort of - these people work on
donations) walking tour for the next day.  While the walking tour was
extremely informative, and our tour guide was very knowledgeable and very
nice, I know that years from now the only thing I'm going to really remember
about it is that the tour took us through the Old Town of Barcelona.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Old Town, consisting of two areas called &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/La_Ribera"&gt;El Born&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gothic_Quarter,_Barcelona"&gt;Gothic
Quarter&lt;/a&gt;, effectively constitutes a giant exception to my idea that
Barcelona doesn't have much of a &amp;quot;vibe&amp;quot;.  The Old Town is &lt;em&gt;all vibe&lt;/em&gt;.  The
entire neighbourhood is bursting with charming little cafes, restaurants,
side streets and alleyways, many of which date back to the medieval era, but
I can't think of a single thing that stuck out more than the neighbourhood
as a whole.  It's very easy to get lost here, and it's very easy not to
care.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And there's a whole set of Roman ruins underneath!  You can buy a ticket to
see them at the local History Museum.  They were discovered relatively
recently; there's a black and white photograph of it in the museum.
Fascinating stuff.  Evelyn and I spent way longer looking at old &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Garum"&gt;garum&lt;/a&gt;
factories than I thought was humanly possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;How To Visit a Beach in Barcelona&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Barcelona actually has a city beach, in the &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/La_Barceloneta,_Barcelona"&gt;Barceloneta&lt;/a&gt; district, that
dates back to 1992, when the city hosted the Olympics.  It's serviceable but
is nonetheless not the one many people think of when they want to take a
dip.  No, the town that crosses everyone's minds when they think of
&amp;quot;Barcelona&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;beaches&amp;quot; is &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/La_Barceloneta,_Barcelona"&gt;Sitges&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, which isn't actually in
Barcelona.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In theory, getting there should have been easy for us.  We were right near
the train station.  It's only a 45 minute ride.  This should have been a
cake walk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alas, we...did not fully understand how the train ticketing system worked,
and ended buying a ticket to someplace completely different.  Luckily,
Evelyn discovered our mistake before we got too far.  Still...28 Euros down
the drain and we only got to Sitges around 4pm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was worth it, though.  The town itself is pretty, sports 17 beaches, none
of which were crowded at that time of year and all of which were beautiful.
The Mediterranean waters were choppy but warm, and became much less choppy
the more you swam out.  I can only imagine how pleasant the excursion would
have been if we had, you know, actually gotten on the right train.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So that's the lesson I took from that day.  Take it from someone who's been
there: make sure you get on the right train!  Words to live by.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Final Thoughts&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Barcelona definitely feels like a place that would reward repeated visits.
I can imagine spending months or even years looking for that one hole in the
wall that serves up the best paella you've ever had, or that one underground
cavern with the secret vermouth barrel that will become the gold standard by
which you will judge all other vermouths.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And it feels more real than Paris, like people actually work and live there.
I think the city isn't burdened by the weight of expectations, and it lets
you have more fun.  I definitely want to go back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe with, you know, some actual Spanish under my belt this time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I mentioned, Barcelona was the first part of a longer trip to Spain.
Stay tuned for my thoughts on Seville and Madrid.&lt;/p&gt;

    </content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title/>
    <link href="https://desmondrivet.com/2024/10/15/154525"/>
    <updated>2024-10-15T19:45:25Z</updated>
    <id>https://desmondrivet.com/2024/10/15/154525</id>
    <content type="html">
        

<p>Reply to <a class="u-in-reply-to dont-break-out" href="https://pixelfed.social/p/nhoizey/751853308530419259">https://pixelfed.social/p/nhoizey/751853308530419259</a></p>


        &lt;p&gt;I recently saw this up close!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://desmondrivet.com/2024/10/05/alcazar/19c08a7be5b784"&gt;https://desmondrivet.com/2024/10/05/alcazar/19c08a7be5b784&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    </content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Spain (September 2024)</title>
    <link href="https://desmondrivet.com/2024/10/05/spain"/>
    <updated>2024-10-06T02:39:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://desmondrivet.com/2024/10/05/spain</id>
    <content type="html">
        


        &lt;p&gt;Evelyn and I took a 10 day trip to Spain in September 2024.&lt;/p&gt;

    </content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title/>
    <link href="https://desmondrivet.com/2024/09/24/165011"/>
    <updated>2024-09-24T20:50:11Z</updated>
    <id>https://desmondrivet.com/2024/09/24/165011</id>
    <content type="html">
        


        &lt;p&gt;Barcelona: Noisy, gritty, vibrant.  Surprisingly many vermouterias.
Seville: Beautiful, charming, fun.  Surprisingly few barbers.&lt;/p&gt;

    </content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title/>
    <link href="https://desmondrivet.com/2024/09/22/135511"/>
    <updated>2024-09-22T17:55:11Z</updated>
    <id>https://desmondrivet.com/2024/09/22/135511</id>
    <content type="html">
        


        &lt;p&gt;There is a glut of vermouterias in Barcelona, many of them with their own house blends and...I kind of love it?&lt;/p&gt;

    </content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title/>
    <link href="https://desmondrivet.com/2024/07/14/140635"/>
    <updated>2024-07-14T18:06:35Z</updated>
    <id>https://desmondrivet.com/2024/07/14/140635</id>
    <content type="html">
        

<p>Bookmark of <a class="u-bookmark-of dont-break-out" href="https://hugocisneros.com/blog/my-org-roam-notes-workflow/">https://hugocisneros.com/blog/my-org-roam-notes-workflow/</a></p>


        
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Yes, I Know That Chai Means Tea</title>
    <link href="https://desmondrivet.com/2024/06/28/chai-tea"/>
    <updated>2024-06-28T14:21:26Z</updated>
    <id>https://desmondrivet.com/2024/06/28/chai-tea</id>
    <content type="html">
        


        &lt;p&gt;Yes, I know that the word &amp;quot;chai&amp;quot; literally just means &amp;quot;tea&amp;quot; in Hindi (and
other languages) and that the term &amp;quot;chai tea&amp;quot; is therefore technically
redundant.  I don't care.  I will still occasionally say &amp;quot;chai tea&amp;quot; and I
don't feel like I'm committing some kind of linguistic sin by doing so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The English translation of &amp;quot;chai&amp;quot; is, of course, &amp;quot;tea&amp;quot; and it refers to a
very generic category of usually hot and often caffeinated beverages made
from steeping various kinds of leaves.  On the other hand, the word &amp;quot;chai&amp;quot;
&lt;em&gt;in English&lt;/em&gt; usually refers to a very specific kind of spiced tea, often
taken with milk, that Westerners typically associate with the culinary
tradition of South Asia.  One would not normally use the word &amp;quot;chai&amp;quot; &lt;em&gt;in
English&lt;/em&gt; to refer to the bog standard Orange Pekoe that one might drink for
a caffeine fix in the morning before work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I &lt;em&gt;could&lt;/em&gt; just use the word &amp;quot;chai&amp;quot; on its own to refer to this spiced
beverage and leave it at that, but if I'm comparing it to other kinds of
tea, like Earl Grey or Irish Breakfast, then I might add the word &amp;quot;tea&amp;quot;
after each item to stress the unifying concept.  So I might say &amp;quot;Earl Grey
tea&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Irish Breakfast tea&amp;quot; or (the horror!) &amp;quot;chai tea&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My point is that the word &amp;quot;chai&amp;quot; &lt;em&gt;in English&lt;/em&gt; doesn't mean the same thing as
it does in other languages, despite being borrowed from those languages.
Sometimes chai is used as more of an adjective than a noun, and that's just
how languages work.  They borrow words and they change them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's exactly the same battle with a word like &amp;quot;naan&amp;quot;.  I know it just means
&amp;quot;bread&amp;quot; in Persian but that's simply not how the word is used in English.
In English it refers to a specific kind of flat bread, usually made in a
specific kind of oven.  I mean, a French baguette is just &amp;quot;bread&amp;quot; as well,
but I suspect you wouldn't use the word &amp;quot;naan&amp;quot; to describe it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And yes, I &lt;em&gt;would&lt;/em&gt; use the (technically redundant) combination &amp;quot;naan bread&amp;quot;
if, like the tea example above, I was trying to differentiate naan from
various other kinds of bread, like sourdough or pita, and I wanted to
emphasize the unifying characteristic of all the things I was talking about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So stop with the sanctimonious word policing, already!  Languages evolve and
trade, and this is just one example in a very long line of examples.&lt;/p&gt;

    </content>
  </entry>
</feed>